Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/dr-adamatandia-3a77b911 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Business Insights
Data Science
Deep Learning

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
French (Native or Bilingual)
Wolof (Native or Bilingual)

Patents

Fusion formable alkali-free intermediate thermal expansion coefficient glass

Five-ring fused heteroaromatic compounds and conjugated polymers thereof

Dihydropyrrolo[2,3-F] indolediketopyrrolopyrrole semiconducting materials, and methods and uses thereof

Dihydropyrrolo[2,3-F] indolediketopyrrolopyrrole semiconducting materials, and methods and uses thereof

Dihydropyrrolo[2,3-F] indolediketopyrrolopyrrole semiconducting materials, and methods and uses thereof

Dr. Adama Tandia

Sr. Research Associate at Corning Incorporated Corning, New York, United States

Summary

Experienced practitioner of Artificial/Augmented Intelligence, Machine Learning, Data Analytics, and Mathematical Modeling. With interest in Al/ML-based new materials discovery, materials design, process modeling & optimization, sensitivity analysis, finance, uncertainty quantification, computer vision, and anomaly detection, NLP

Passionate about innovation, knowledge sharing, and developing others.

Co-inventor of many glasses and polymers at Corning, including Corning Astra (R) Glass for high resolution display.

Problem solver, inventor, team leader, and people developer.

https://www.corning.com/worldwide/en/products/display-glass/products/corning-astra-glass.html

Experience

Corning Incorporated
Sr. Research Associate
December 2000 - Present (22 years 5 months)
Corning, New York

Use of Artificial Intelligence for Machine Learning, Data Analytics,
Manufacturing Process Optimization, Materials modeling and Design (glass,
polymers, polar liquids), and Anomalies Detection
Inventer of polymers, glasses, and Al /ML learning and training algorithms
Problem solver, and people developer & enabler
Team leader with impactful achievements

Northwestern University
Engineering Science and Applied Mathematics - Research
February 1998 - November 2000 (2 years 10 months)
Evanston, IL (USA)

Level Set Methods Stochastic Methods Numerical Methods Probability

LAAS-CNRS

Research Scientist

February 1994 - January 1998 (4 years)

Toulouse, France

Application of stochastic methods to Si/SiO2 interface characterization Neural Networks for Process Control

Monte Carlo

DFT

Education

Université Paul Sabatier (Toulouse III)

Ph.D., Physics / Applied Mathematics · (1994 - 1998)

Université Paris-Est Créteil (UPEC)

Master, Physics & Applied Math · (1993 - 1994)

University Cheikh Anta Diop

Bachelor, Applied Physics/Applied Mathematics · (1987 - 1992)